Darren M Smith

Email: dxsmith12@soverin.net | Phone: 703.927.8456 | Chesterfield VA 23832

GitHub: https://github.com/thedern | Website: https://github.com/thedern | Website: https://github.com/thedern | Website: https://thedern.github.io | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/dxsmith12

SUMMARY

IT professional turned web developer with experience in e-commerce supporting both backend systems as well as frontend, customer facing applications. Highly motivated learner pursuing a certification from University of Richmond Full Stack Web Development bootcamp. Possesses strong skills in frontend technologies such as html, css, javascript, jQuery, react as well as skills in server-side technologies such as, node.js, python, and bash. Excited about useful and creative web design and its impact on people's lives.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

University of Richmond, Richmond VA - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp - May 2019' Intensive, project-based curriculum focused on full stack web development, specifically the MERN stack

CompTIA Cloud Essentials - Certification, 12/2017 CompTIA Security+ - Certification, 7/2016

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Certification, 11/2017 CompTIA Network+ - Certification, 5/2017

Radford University, Radford VA - Biology Cum Laude - 1997

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS; javascript; React; jQuery; node.js; express; python; jython; bootstrap 4; shell; sql; Firebase; Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu); Amazon Web Services; Apache/Tomcat Server; WebSphere; MySQL; MongoDB

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Lead Developer

- **Barnyard Word Guess** A game developed in html, css, bootstrap, and javascript for preschool aged children facilitating practice with the alphabet
- Gems A blackjack-like numbers game developed in html, css, bootstrap, and javascript
- **Gif Search** An api driven app developed in html, css, bootstrap, and javascript/ajax that provides a search interface for Giffs
- **Holiday Train Schedule** An app developed in html, css, bootstrap, firebase and javascript/ajax that utilizes Firebase for persistent storage of a mock train station schedule
- **Bamazon Store** A text based shopping application written in node.js utilizing mysql to create, read, update, and delete store inventory based on user input.
- **Liri App** A text based search application written in node.js that utilizes axios as well as other packages to make api calls to return data in response to user input
- **Express Weather** A weather search application written in node.js using express as well as other api's in order to return weather search results.

- **Friend Finder** A personality compatibility application written in node.js, express, and views engines in order to render the user interface.
- **Zenburger** A MVC application using node.js, express, mysql, and views engines in order to create, read, update, and delete information based on the users input, text and click events.
- InterRxact A react.js application which assists users in discovering potentially dangerous prescription drug interactions and side effects.

See https://thedern.github.io/#homework for links to applications and screen cast demos.

EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer IV / Full Stack Developer

Advance Autoparts Inc.

2011-Present Richmond, VA

- Member of e-Commerce dev team tasked with converting consumer website code from jQuery to React.js
- Member of a team of IT professionals tasked with the deployment and maintenance of retail and wholesale e-commerce sites (advanceautoparts.com / advancecommercial.com) which generate over \$500 million in net sales annually.
- Develops python and jython utilities for the automation of applications server tasks as well as for research endeavors such as infrastructure analysis and web server log scraping
- Deploys web application code (html, css, js, java) to production e-commerce websites
- Maintains site's web and application server software, ensuring uptime and availability to customers
- Works closely with web application developers remediating code-related errors ensuring functionality and usability, protecting company revenue

Senior Middleware Administrator

2010-2011

Federal Reserve IT (FRIT); Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond

Richmond, VA

- Technical support engineer for Federal Reserve banking systems internal web-based applications which provide services and support to the Nation's banking systems.
- Responsibilities included 24x7 support for web-based banking systems, technology roadmapping, systems design and implementation, technical documentation, and internal customer engagement/training.

Consultant - Senior Systems Administrator

2005-2010

Circuit City Stores Inc.

Richmond, VA

- Web-based application systems administrator supporting both internal web-based systems as well as the consumer-facing e-commerce site, *circuitcity.com*.
- Provided 24x7 support for *circuitcity.com* which included deploying code (html, css, js, and java) as well as ensuring site uptime and security.
- Work closely with developers remediating code-related errors ensuring functionality and usability, protecting company revenue
- Member of e-commerce 'Black Friday/Cyber Monday' support team ensuring website uptime and performance on most important retail days of the year.
- Internally, provided support to development teams during regular business hours via maintaining both web and application servers used for e-commerce application development.